

# Lindita Nerguti

## Senior integrative counsellor and psychotherapist

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: <a href="mailto:info@healthcity.org.uk/">info@healthcity.org.uk/</a> Website: <a href="https://healthcity.org.uk/">https://healthcity.org.uk/</a>

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

A well-organised and hardworking person with a vast experience in immigration law and welfare benefits. Skilled in communication effectively with people of different backgrounds; experienced in interviewing them tactfully and diplomatically. A good team member, self motivated with the ability to motivate others. Highly experienced in working under pressure and displaying creativity, ability to take decisions in different situations and circumstances. A very reliable person.

## **EXPERIENCE:**

- ❖ I have developed professional interviewing skills with people of different backgrounds and complex problems displaying excellent listening, observing and analysing skills in reaching fair conclusions.
- ❖ Performed complex duties and skilled in working under pressure in difficult circumstances.
- ❖ Established professional links with a variety of organisations and institutions evaluating different sources of the data used in my profession.
- ❖ Gained secretarial skills in writing reports, completing files and keeping data for the work with clients. Enhanced reception skills both through phone and in person, good command of typing work.
- ❖ I have displayed commitment to my job, creative thinking while working with clients especially with refugees, asylum seekers and unaccompanied children.
- ❖ Working with refugees, asylum seekers and unaccompanied children in counselling, advising, interpreting or translation contexts has given me the profound knowledge of their situation and their issues or problems.
- ❖ Skilled in listening and advising people who are in hopeless, stressed situations, helping them to overcome these situations, stressing the positive aspects to clients.

### **MANAGEMENT:**

- Skilled in planning of the work and the load undertaken, which requires prioritising key issues.
- ❖ Gained time-management skills to allocate the needed time and to evaluate the importance of each stage of the work with the clients.
- ❖ I am well aware of the boundaries and the responsibility required in working with people displayed while working in counselling and advice practice.
- ❖ I have achieved high skills in working independently with high confidence.
- Self motivated with the ability to motivate others creating a good team spirit and achieving the highest results in my work within community context.
- ❖ I have worked under pressure gaining the ability to cope in complex situations and evaluate

priorities.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:**

Jan2014- Continous CLERICAL OFFICER (PART-TIME)

Moorfields Eye Hospital, London

Nov 2007-Continues OUTREACH ADVICE WORKER (PART -TIME)

South Bromley Forum, London

Feb 2008-July 2008 COMMUNITY WORKER

Lansbury Lodge Women Project

Jan 2002-May 2008 COUNSELLOR & PSYCHOTHERAPIST

Community Health Project (Changed to "Community Health Centre")

Feb 2000-Jul 2002 ASYLUM SUPPORT ADVISER

INTERPRETER/ADMIN-WORK Refugee Advice Centre, Leyton.

2000-2003 WELFARE BENEFITADVISER/

INTERPRETER/ADMIN-WORK

'Shqiponja', Albanian Community Organization

Oct 2001- Oct 2002 INTERPRETER AND TRANSLATOR

Forest Care Services Ltd (unaccompanied children)

1989-1998 PUBLIC PROSECUTOR

Kukes District, Albania

# **EDUCATION HISTORY:**

2002-2004 POSTGRADUATED DIPLOMA IN COUNSELLING &PSYCHOTHERAPY

University of East London

2002 CERTIFICATE IN ADVICE AND GUIDANCE (NVQ 3)

City Islington College

2002 CERTIFICATE OF LEVEL 2 ASYLUM (ATTENDANCE)

University of London

1985-1989 DIPLOMA IN LAW AND JUSTICE

Tirana University, Albania.

**REFERENCES** Available on request